George Middleton Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
George Middleton Papers 1872-1970 1911-1958
MSS32839
Middleton, George, 1880-1967
15,000 items
85 containers plus 8 oversize
36.6 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Playwright, author, and copyright specialist. Correspondence, literary manuscripts, subject files, and research material and documenting Middleton's career as a playwright, author, and copyright specialist at the Department of Justice. Also includes correspondence relating to the La Follette and Middleton families.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Barrie, J. M. (James Matthew), 1860-1937--Correspondence.; Belasco, David, 1853-1931.; Bolton, Guy, 1884-1979.; Brandeis, Louis Dembitz, 1856-1941--Correspondence.; DeMille, Cecil B. (Cecil Blount), 1881-1959--Correspondence.; Dos Passos, John, 1896-1970--Correspondence.; Duse, Eleonora, 1858-1924--Correspondence.; France, Anatole, 1844-1924--Correspondence.; Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965--Correspondence.; Garland, Hamlin, 1860-1940--Correspondence.; Hart, Moss, 1904-1961--Correspondence.; Kaufman, George S. (George Simon), 1889-1961--Correspondence.; La Follette family--Correspondence.; La Follette, Fola, 1882-1970--Correspondence.; La Follette, Fola, 1882-1970.; La Follette, Robert M. (Robert Marion), 1855-1925.; Lewis, Sinclair, 1885-1951--Correspondence.; Lilienthal, David Eli, 1899-1981--Correspondence.; MacKaye, Percy, 1875-1956--Correspondence.; Marquis, Don, 1878-1937--Correspondence.; Masefield, John, 1878-1967--Correspondence.; Masters, Edgar Lee, 1868-1950--Correspondence.; Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956--Correspondence.; Middleton family--Correspondence.; Middleton, George, 1880-1967.; Middleton, George, 1880-1967. These things are mine. 1947.; Nye, Gerald P. (Gerald Prentice), 1892-1971--Correspondence.; O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953--Correspondence.; Odets, Clifford, 1906-1963--Correspondence.; Rodgers, Richard, 1902-1979--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945--Correspondence.; Shaw, Bernard, 1856-1950--Correspondence.; Steffens, Lincoln, 1866-1936--Correspondence.; Tarkington, Booth, 1869-1946--Correspondence.; Wodehouse, P. G. (Pelham Grenville), 1881-1975--Correspondence.; Wood, Peggy, 1892-1978--Correspondence.
Organizations
Dramatists Guild.; Dutch Treat Club.; Players (Club); United States. Department of Justice.
Subjects
Copyright--Performing rights.; Copyright.; Drama--Societies, etc.; Presidents--United States--Election--1924.; Theater.
Places
United States--Intellectual life--20th century.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.
Occupations
Authors.; Copyright specialists.; Dramatists.
Acquisition Information
The papers of George Middleton, playwright, author, and copyright specialist, were given to the Library of Congress by his wife, Fola La Follette, in 1969. Subsequent gifts, originally acquired as part of the La Follette Family Papers, were added to the collection by Mary La Follette, 1970-1971.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of George Middleton are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1880, Oct. 27 Born, Paterson, New Jersey
1902 Graduated from Columbia University, New York, N.Y. First professional play, The Cavalier, produced
1903 Joined The Players, a club for representative members of the dramatic arts and other related professions
1911 Published Embers. New York: H. Holt and Co. (first volume of one-act plays) Married Fola La Follette
1913 Joined the Authors League of America Published Tradition. New York: H. Holt and Co.(second volume of one-act plays)
1915 Published Possession. New York: H. Holt and Co. (third volume of one-act plays) Produced Hit-the-Trail-Holliday, play coauthored with Guy Bolton, adapted by George M. Cohan
1917 Produced Polly with a Past, play coauthored with Guy Bolton
1919 Produced Adam and Eva, play coauthored with Guy Bolton
1920 Published Masks. New York: S. French., fourth volume of one-act plays
1922 Elected to the Dutch Treat Club
1927 1929 President, Dramatists Guild
1928 Represented Authors League at Congress of the International Confederation of Societies of Authors and Composers, Berlin, Germany
1929 1931 Associate producer and writer, Fox Film Corporation in Hollywood
1933 Published Hiss! Boom!! Blah!!! New York: S. French
1936 Published That Was Balzac. New York: Random House
1942 1958 Technical specialist in copyright law, Office of Alien Property, Justice Department
1947 Published autobiography, These Things Are Mine. New York: Macmillan Co.
1955 Turnabout in manuscript form the first American play copyrighted under the New Universal Copyright convention
1957 Sustained Superior Performance Award, Justice Department
1967, Dec. 23 Died, Washington, D.C.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of George Middleton (1880-1967) span the years 1872-1970 with the bulk of the material between 1911 and 1958. The collection is composed of correspondence and literary manuscripts organized into the following series: Family Correspondence, General Correspondence, Business Correspondence, Subject File, Literary Manuscripts, Miscellany, and Addition. The material is in English, with some in French.
The Family Correspondence consists of letters written to his wife, Fola La Follette, and to his brother, nephew, and his wife's family about the many activities, places, and people he was involved with as a playwright and as a representative of the writing profession abroad. Events relating to the 1924 presidential campaign of Robert M. La Follette (1855-1925) are also chronicled in Middleton's correspondence with his wife and the La Follette family.
The General Correspondence contains letters from a broad segment of the theatrical, literary, and governmental communities. Among the correspondents are J. M. Barrie, Cecil B. DeMille, Eleanora Duse, Moss Hart, George S. Kaufman, Richard Rodgers, and Peggy Wood from the theatrical community; John Dos Passos, Anatole France, Hamlin Garland, Sinclair Lewis, Percy Mackaye, Don Marquis, John Masefield, Edgar Lee Masters, H. L. Mencken, Clifford Odets, Eugene O'Neill, Bernard Shaw, Lincoln Steffens, Booth Tarkington, and P. G. Wodehouse from the literary community; and Louis Dembitz Brandeis, Felix Frankfurter, David Eli Lilienthal, Gerald P. Nye, and Franklin D. Roosevelt and Eleanor Roosevelt in the governmental community.
The Business Correspondence documents the publication and production of Middleton's plays and articles, his collaboration with David Belasco and Guy Bolton, and his relationship with various agents, producers, and managers.
Of particular interest in the Subject File are papers relating to the Dramatists Guild, of which Middleton was a founding member, and the fight to protect foreign and domestic playwrights' monetary and literary rights in the production and publication of their works. Middleton's service as a copyright specialist in the Justice Department is documented under the headings "Office of Alien Property," "copyright legislation," and "copyrights." Middleton's social relationships with the theatrical community are documented in files relating to the Dutch Treat Club and to Players Club. Important biographical information about Middleton is contained in the "Who's Who" file.
The Literary Manuscripts series contains succeeding drafts, as well as final typescripts or printed versions, of all of Middleton's plays and of his autobiography, These Things Are Mine. In many cases photographs of stage sets and actors and actresses accompany the manuscripts. A large part of the autobiographical material consists of research material and family memorabilia that Middleton collected for his writings. Film scripts on which Middleton worked while a producer-writer with the Fox Film Corporation in 1929-1931 are also included. In addition to his books and plays, the series also documents Middleton's articles, book reviews, early literary writings, lectures, poetry, and stories.
The remainder of the collection consists of family photographs, miscellaneous papers, a card index that Middleton keyed to his correspondence, and his collection of Balzaciana. Scrapbooks include articles written by Middleton on the theater for various newspapers and journals, press reviews, publicity and programs for his plays, and letters of congratulations on his eightieth birthday.
An addition appended to the original arrangement in 1979 spans the period 1879-1970, with the major part dating from 1953 to 1967. Correspondence of George Middleton and Fola La Follette with members of the Middleton and La Follette families is included in the Addition, as is Middleton's correspondence with various friends and associates. This material supplements that found in corresponding series in the main body of the collection.
Much of the material in the headings grouped under the subject file and miscellany subseries of the Addition relates to topics of a personal or family interest. Correspondence and printed matter pertaining to Middleton's involvement in theatrical and literary organizations such as the Dramatists Guild and the Authors League of America are also included.
Carbon copies of typescripts of poems are contained under the speeches and writings heading, as is a final typescript of Middleton's unpublished novel, "A Prisoner of Fame."
Organization of the Papers
The collection is arranged in seven series:
Family Correspondence, 1872-1968
General Correspondence, 1901-1967
Business Correspondence, 1903-1967
Subject File, 1901-1967
Literary Manuscripts, 1874-1963
Miscellany, 1898-1967
Addition, 1879-1970
Container List
- Family Correspondence, 1872-1968 (Box 1-2)
  Letters received and copies of letters sent.
  Correspondence with wife, Fola La Follette, is arranged chronologically; the other correspondence is divided into two general sections, Middleton family and La Follette family, with some entries by name of correspondent.
  - Selected letters of George Middleton to his wife, Fola La Follette, 1921-1963, undated, and several letters from Fola La Follette to Middleton, 1924, 1935 (Box 1)
  - La Follette family (Box 2)
    - La Follette, Belle Case, letters sent and letters received, 1912, undated
    - La Follette, Bronson, and family, 1963-1967
    - La Follette, Fola, 1918, 1968
    - La Follette, Joseph, and family, 1965-1966, undated
    - La Follette, Philip, and family, 1936-1965
    - La Follette, Robert (1895-1953), and family, 1936-1960, undated
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, undated
  - Middleton family
    - George Middleton's letters to his parents and grandmother, 1894, undated
    - Letters received from parents and from grandmother and grandfather Middleton, 1894-1920
    - Letters from Middleton's grandfather to his father, George Middleton, Sr., 1872
    - Telegram to mother, Ida Blakesley Middleton, 1929
    - Letters received and copies of letters sent to brother, Scudder Middleton, 1928-1959, undated
    - Letters received and copies of letters sent to nephew, David Middleton, 1936-1967
    - Middleton family correspondence, letters received from cousin, Mrs. John Jay Joyce, 1962
    - Letters received and copies of letters sent to cousins, Blakeslee Dunphy, his wife Virginia, and daughter Priscilla (and Charles Burlingham), 1939-1967
- General Correspondence, 1901-1967 (Box 3-17)
  Letters received and copies of letters sent, memoranda, printed material, photographs, newspaper clippings, and other material relating to the correspondent.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - "A" miscellany (Box 3)
  - Abbott, George
  - Adamic, Louis
  - Adams, John Wolcott
  - Adams, Maude
  - Addams, Jane
  - Aherne, Brian
  - Allen, Hervey
  - Allen, Viola
  - Ames, Winthrop
  - Amiel, Denys
  - Anderson, Judith
  - Anderson, Maxwell
  - Anderson, Robert
  - Andrews, Mary Shipman
  - Anglin, Margaret
  - Anspacher, Louis K.
  - Anson, A. E.
  - Anthony, Ed and Esther
  - Anthony, Katharine
  - Arbos, E. Fernandez
  - Archer, William
  - Arliss, George
  - Arnold, Thurman
  - Arnoux, Alexandre and Amelia
  - Atherton, Gertrude
  - Atkinson, Brooks
  - Aynesworth, Allan
  - "B" miscellany (Box 4)
  - Bacheller, Irving
  - Bacon, Leonard
  - Bainter, Fay
  - Baker, George Barr
  - Baker, George Pierce
  - Baker, Ray Stannard
  - Balch, David A.
  - Baldwin, Roger
  - Bangs, John Kendrick
  - Banks, Leslie
  - Banks, Nancy Houstin
  - Barnes, Eric Wollencott
  - Barnsdall, Aline
  - Barrie, James M.
  - Barrymore, John
  - Bates, Blanche
  - Beach, Rex
  - Beard, Charles and Mary
  - Behrman, Sam
  - Beith, Ian Hay
  - Belasco, David
  - Bennett, Arnold
  - Bennett, Richard
  - Benton, William
  - Berle, Adolf
  - Bernstein, Aline
  - Bernstein, Henry
  - Bernstein, Leonard
  - Bingham, Amelia
  - Bjorkman, Edwin
  - Blackwell, Alice Stone
  - Blinn, Holbrook
  - Block, Anita
  - Bodanzky, Arthur
  - Bojer, Johan
  - Bolton, Guy
  - Bone, Homer T.
  - Borchard, Edwin M.
  - Borgnine, Ernest
  - Bourdet, Edouard (Box 5)
  - Bouteron, Marcel
  - Bowers, Claude
  - Bowes, Major Edward
  - Bowman, John G.
  - Boynton, Henry Walcott
  - Bradley, Jennie Serruys (Mrs. William A.)
  - Brady, William A.
  - Bragdon, Claude
  - Braithwaite, William Stanley
  - Brandeis, Louis and Alice
  - Brandt, Carl
  - Brieux, Eugene
  - Brooks, Van Wyck
  - Brown, Francis
  - Brown, Ivor
  - Brown, John Mason
  - Brynner, Yul
  - Buchanan, Thompson
  - Buck, Gene
  - Bullard, Arthur
  - Bunau-Varilla, Philippe
  - Burke, Billie
  - Burnett, Frances Hodgson
  - Burton, Richard
  - Bynner, Witter
  - "C" miscellany (Box 6)
  - Cable, George Washington
  - Calthrop, Donald
  - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick
  - Canby, Henry Seidel
  - Cane, Melville
  - Carpenter, George R.
  - Carroll, Paul V.
  - Cartwright, Charles
  - Cassado
  - Catledge, Turner
  - Cerf, Bennett
  - Chamberlain, John
  - Chamlee, Mario
  - Chandler, Frank W.
  - Chapman, Oscar
  - Chase, Joseph Cummings
  - Chevalier, Maurice
  - Churchill, Allen
  - Chute, Marchette and Joy
  - Claire, Ina
  - Clark, Barrett
  - Clark, Bennett C.
  - Clark, Joseph S.
  - Clark, Tom C.
  - Claudel, Paul
  - Cleveland, Harlan
  - Cobb, Irvin S.
  - Coburn, Charles
  - Cohan, George M.
  - Collinge, Patricia
  - Colum, Padraic
  - Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
  - Commager, Henry Steele
  - Connally, Marc
  - Coolus, Romain
  - Cooper, Gladys
  - Copeou, Jacques
  - Corbett, James J.
  - Corbin, John
  - Cornell, Katharine
  - Cosgrave, John O'Hara
  - Costa, Leon de
  - Coward, Noel
  - Cowl, Jane
  - Cox, Oscar
  - Craven, Frank
  - Creighton, Thomas
  - Croker, B. M.
  - Crosmann, Henrietta
  - Crothers, Rachel
  - Crouse, Russel
  - Crowninshield, Frank
  - Croy, Homer
  - "D" miscellany (Box 7)
  - Daly, Arnold
  - Dargan, E. Preston
  - Dargan, Olive
  - Davidson, Jo
  - Davis, Elmer
  - Davis, Owen, (2 folders)
  - Davis, William Hammatt and Donald
  - Dean, Basil
  - De Foe, Louis V.
  - De Kolra, Maurice
  - DeMille, Cecil B., Agnes, and William C.
  - Dewey, John
  - Dewing, Thomas W.
  - Dickson, Harris
  - Ditrichstein, Leo
  - Dixon, Thomas
  - Dos Passos, John
  - Downes, Olin
  - Drinkwater, John
  - Dunning, Philip
  - Duranty, Walter
  - Duse, Eleanora
  - "E" miscellany
  - Eaton, Walter B.
  - Edeson, Robert
  - Elder, William V.
  - Elliott, Maxine
  - Ellis, Mary
  - Ernst, Morris
  - Erskine, John
  - Ervine, St. John
  - Evans, Maurice
  - Eyre, Lawrence
  - "F" miscellany
  - Fairbanks, Douglas
  - Faversham, William
  - Ferber, Edna
  - Ferguson, Elsie
  - Ferrer, José
  - Fisher, Arthur
  - Fisher, Lola
  - Fiske, Minnie Maddern and Harrison Grey
  - Fitch, Clyde
  - Flain, Martin
  - Flexner, Abraham
  - Folger, J. Clifford
  - France, Anatole
  - Frankfurter, Felix
  - Freedley, George
  - Freedman, Harold
  - Freeman, Max
  - French dramatists and writers
  - French embassy
  - Frohman, Charles and Daniel
  - "G" miscellany (Box 8)
  - Gale, Zona
  - Galsworthy, John
  - Garland, Hamlin
  - Garrison, Lloyd
  - Gaus, John
  - Geddes, Norman Bel
  - Gémier, Firmin
  - Gielgud, John
  - Gilbert, Douglas
  - Gilbert, Giles
  - Gillette, William
  - Gish, Lillian
  - Glaenzer, Richard Butler
  - Glaser, Lulu
  - Goldman, Emma
  - Goodman, Jules Eckert
  - Gordon, Ruth
  - Gottschalk, Ferdinand
  - Graham, Philip
  - Granville-Barker, Harley
  - Green, Abel
  - Greenstreet, Sydney
  - Grierson, Francis
  - Griffith, Kate
  - Gruening, Ernest
  - Guilbert, Yvette
  - Gurity, Sacha, (2 folders)
  - Guitry, Sacha, and Yvonne Printemps
  - Guthrie, Sir Tyrone
  - Guthrie, William N.
  - "H" miscellany (Box 9)
  - Hackett, James K.
  - Hale, Gardner
  - Hamilton, Clayton
  - Hammerstein, Oscar, II
  - Hammond, Percy
  - Hampden, Walter
  - Hansen, Harry
  - Hard, William
  - Hardwicke, Sir Cedric
  - Harris, Julie
  - Harris, Sam
  - Harrison, Henry Sydnor
  - Hart, Moss
  - Hart, Philip A.
  - Hastings, W. Scott
  - Hayes, Helen
  - Hays, Arthur Garfield
  - Hazard, Paul
  - Heckscher, August
  - Hellman, Lillian
  - Henderson, Archibald
  - Hendricks, Burton
  - Hepburn, Katharine
  - Herford, Olive
  - Higginson, Thomas Wentworth
  - Hill, Lister
  - Hilton, James
  - Hobart, Garret A.
  - Holland, Edmund Milton
  - Holmes, John Haynes
  - Hooker, Brian
  - Hopkins, Arthur
  - Horniman, Annie Elizabeth Fredericka
  - Howard, Sidney
  - Howe, P. P.
  - Huebsch, Ben
  - Hughes, Rupert
  - Hume, Paul
  - Humphrey, Hubert H.
  - Hunneker, James
  - Hurst, Fannie
  - Huston, John
  - Huston, Walter
  - Hutchins, John H.
  - Irving, Lawrence
  - Irwin, Will and Onez
  - "J" miscellany (Box 10)
  - Jackson, Charles Tenney
  - Johnson, Alvin
  - Johnson, James Weldon
  - Johnson, Lyndon B.
  - Johnston, Mary
  - Jones, Henry Arthur
  - Jones, Robert Edmond
  - "K" miscellany
  - Kallen, Horace M.
  - Kaufman, George S.
  - Kazan, Elia
  - Keane, Doris
  - Kelland, Clarence B.
  - Kelly, George
  - Kelly, Renée
  - Kemp, Harry
  - Kennedy, Edward M.
  - Kennedy, John F. and Jacqueline
  - Kennedy, Robert F. and Ethel
  - Kenton, Edna
  - Kepple, Fred
  - Kerr, Jean
  - Kester, Paul
  - Knoblock, Edward
  - Knopf, Edwin, Alfred, and Mildred O.
  - Korda, Sir Alexander
  - "L" miscellany (Box 11)
  - Labouisse, Eve Curie
  - Lacoste, Francis
  - La Follette family See Container 2, same heading
  - Lambiotte, Auguste and Rose
  - Landowska, Wanda
  - Langner, Lawrence
  - Lanux, Jeanne and Pierre de
  - Larrimore, Francine
  - Lasky, Jesse L.
  - Latham, Harold S.
  - Laughton, Charles
  - Laurence, Dan
  - LaVerne, Lucille
  - Lavery, Emmet
  - Le Gallienne, Eva
  - Le Gallienne, Richard
  - LeMoyne, Sarah Cowell
  - Lenormand, Henri René
  - Lewis, Lloyd
  - Lewis, Sinclair
  - Lilienthal, David
  - Lindbergh, Charles
  - Lindey, Alexander
  - Lindsay, Howard
  - Lindsay, John V.
  - Lindsey, Ben B.
  - Lippmann, Walter
  - Lohr, Marie
  - Long, Russell E.
  - Lord, Pauline
  - Lunt, Alfred, and Fontanne, Lynn
  - "M" miscellany (Box 12)
  - MacCarthy, Justin Huntly
  - Mack, Willard
  - MacKaye, Percy
  - MacLeish, Archibald
  - Malone, Dudley Field
  - Mamoulian, Rouben
  - Mann, Louis, and Clara Lipman
  - Mann, Thomas
  - Mansfield, Richard
  - March, Fredric
  - Marks, Josephine Peabody
  - Marlowe, Julia, (2 folders)
  - Marquis, Don
  - Masefield, John
  - Massey, Raymond
  - Masters, Edgar Lee
  - Matthews, Brander
  - Maude, Cyril
  - Maugham, W. Somerset
  - Maurice, Arthur and Flora Mae Holly
  - Maurois, André
  - Maxwell, W. B.
  - McClellan, John L.
  - McClintic, Guthrie See Container 6, Cornell, Katharine
  - McGrath, Harold
  - Mead, James M. (Box 13)
  - Megrue, Roi Cooper
  - Mencken, Henry Louis
  - Meredith, George
  - Miller, Gilbert
  - Miller, Henry
  - Moffett, Cleveland
  - Moley, Raymond
  - Molnar, Ferenc
  - Monroney, A. S.
  - Morehouse, Ward
  - Morley, Christopher
  - Morley, Robert
  - Morris, Lloyd
  - Morse, Wayne
  - Mumford, Quincy L.
  - Muni, Paul
  - "N" miscellany
  - Nazimova, Alla
  - Neagoe, Peter
  - Nevins, Allan and Mary
  - New York Times
  - Nichols, Dudley
  - Nicholson, Meredith
  - Nillson, Carlotta
  - Nock, Albert Jay
  - Noyes, Alfred
  - Nye, Gerald P.
  - Oberdorfer, Louis F. (Box 14)
  - O'Connor, Bessie (Mrs. T. P.)
  - Odell, George
  - Odets, Clifford
  - Oenslager, Donald
  - Olivier, Laurence
  - O'Neill, Eugene, (2 folders)
  - Osborn, E. B.
  - Otto, Max
  - "P" miscellany
  - Paine, Albert Bigelow
  - Palmer, Paul
  - Payne, B. Iden
  - Peirce, Waldo
  - Pemberton, Brock
  - Perkins, Frances
  - Perry, Bliss
  - Peyre, Henri M.
  - Phelps, William Lyon
  - Phillips, John S.
  - Pidgin, Charles Felton
  - Pierce, Roger and Sandra
  - Pinero, Sir Arthur
  - Pollock, Channing
  - Post, Melville Davisson
  - Pratt, Caroline
  - Pugh, Ethel (Mrs. Charles Henry)
  - Putnam, Nina Wilcox
  - "Q" miscellany (Box 15)
  - "R" miscellany
  - Rains, Claude
  - Rambeau, Marjorie
  - Randall, Ruth
  - Raphael, Alice
  - Rehan, Ada
  - Reicher, Emanuel
  - Reinhardt, Max
  - Reinheimer, Howard
  - Rice, Alice Hegan
  - Rice, Elmer
  - Richman, Arthur
  - Ringwalt, Ralph Curtis
  - Rivoire, André
  - Roberts, Florence
  - Roberts, Kenneth
  - Robertson-Forbes, Gertrude
  - Robins, Raymond
  - Robinson, Boardman
  - Robinson, Edward G.
  - Robinson, Francis
  - Rodgers, Richard
  - Roe, Jack and Netha
  - Rogers, Merrill
  - Rogers, Will
  - Rogers, William P.
  - Romains, Jules
  - Romberg, Sigmund
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D. and Eleanor
  - Royce, William Howard
  - Rutledge, Maryse
  - "S" miscellany (Box 16)
  - Sandburg, Helga
  - Sargeant, Howlend H.
  - Scheu-Riesz, Helene
  - Schlesinger, Arthur Meier (1917-2007)
  - Schnitzler, Arthur
  - Shaw, George Bernard, (3 folders)
  - Shearer, Norma
  - Sheehan, Winfield
  - Sheldon, Edward
  - Sherwood, Robert
  - Shipman, Louis Evan
  - Shumlin, Herman
  - Sil-Vara, G. A.
  - Sinclair, Upton
  - Skinner, Otis and Cornelia
  - Smith, Harry
  - Smith, Winchell
  - Sothern, Edward Hugh
  - Spewack, Bella
  - Stebbins, Rowland
  - Steele, Frederic Dorr
  - Steffins, Lincoln
  - Stein, Gertrude
  - Stevenson, Adlai E.
  - Stowe, Lyman Beecher
  - Stokowski, Leopold
  - Stravinsky, Igor
  - Strong, Austin
  - Sullivan, Frank
  - Sulzberger, Arthur Hays
  - Tachau, William G. (Box 17)
  - Taft, Martha Wheaton Bowers
  - Tarkington, Booth
  - Taubman, Howard
  - Taylor, Deems
  - Taylor, Laurette
  - Taylor, Samuel
  - Tearle, Godfrey
  - Tenzer, Herbert
  - Terry, Fred
  - Thomas, Albert Ellsworth and Ethel
  - Thompson, Dorothy
  - Thorndike, Dame Sybil
  - Thring, Ida Sybil
  - Tibbett, Lawrence
  - Towne, Charles Hanson
  - Townsend, Dallas
  - Truman, Harry S.
  - Tsurimi, Yusuke
  - Tweedsmuir, John Norman Stuart Buchan, Baron, and Lady Susan
  - Tyler, George
  - "V" miscellany
  - Van Druten, John
  - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem
  - Veiller, Bayard
  - Villard, Oswald Garrison
  - "W" miscellany
  - Wagner, Robert F.
  - Wald, Lillian D.
  - Walker, Charlotte
  - Warfield, David
  - Webster, Peggy
  - Welles, Orson
  - Whitlock, Brand
  - Wilcox, Ella Wheeler
  - Willard, Edward
  - Williams, Emlyn
  - Williams, Jesse Lynch
  - Wilson, Francis
  - Wodehouse, P. G.
  - Wood, Peggy
  - Woodberry, George
  - Woollcott, Alexander
  - Wouk, Herman
  - Young, Stanley
  - Yurka, Blanche
  - Zueblin
  - Zweig, Stefan
  - Unidentified
- Business Correspondence, 1903-1967 (Box 18-23)